themaven.net 2018-06-30

# Privacy Policy - Maven

  *  Home

We at Maven operate a digital media platform enabling publishers (known as **Channel Partners** ) to publish content on their own web pages (known as **Channels** ) within the websites listed [here](https://www.themaven.net/the-maven/pages/list-of-domains-Kzn9RjgXn0uEVn-85yM19Q/) and related mobile applications (together, the **websites** ). This Privacy Policy sets out how we and our Channel Partners, collect, store and use information about you when you use or interact with the websites and the Channels, and where we otherwise obtain or collect information about you. This Privacy Policy does not generally apply to information collected by third parties other than Channel Partners via the websites. This Privacy Policy is effective from May 25, 2018.

This section is a summary of how we, Maven Coalition, Inc., and the Channel Partner with respect to any Channel you may visit, obtain, store and use information about you. For a full understanding, you should read this summary in conjunction with the corresponding full sections of this Privacy Policy.

● **How we collect or obtain information about you** : when you provide it to us (e.g., by contacting us, by filling in forms on the websites, by registering to use the websites, by posting comments or stories on the websites, by placing an order on the websites or by electing to “follow” a particular channel on the websites), and from your use of the websites, using cookies and similar technologies.

● **Information we collect** : name, contact details, IP address, information from cookies, information about your computer or device (e.g. device and browser type), information about how you use the websites (e.g. which pages you have viewed, the time when you view them and what you clicked on) and the geographical location from which you accessed the websites (based on your IP address).

● **How we use your information** : to present the websites and Channels to you, for administrative and business purposes (particularly to contact you and process orders you place on the websites), to improve our business and website, to fulfil our contractual obligations, to analyze your use of the websites, in connection with our legal rights and obligations, to fulfil any other purpose for which you provide it, to provide you with notices about your account, including expiration and renewal notices.

● **Disclosure of your information to third parties** : only to the extent necessary to run our business, to our service providers, to fulfil any contracts we enter into with you and where required by law or to enforce our legal rights.

● **Do we sell your information to third parties (other than in the course of a business sale or purchase or similar event)** : No.

● **How long we retain your information** : until you request that we delete it, taking into account any legal obligations we have (e.g., to maintain records for tax purposes), any other legal basis we have for using your information (e.g., your consent, performance of a contract with you or our legitimate interests as a business). For specific retention periods in relation to certain information which we collect from you, please see the main section below entitled **How long we retain your information**.

● **How we secure your information** : using appropriate technical and organizational measures such as storing your information on secure servers, encrypting transfers of data to or from our servers using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology, encrypting payments you make on or via the websites using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology, only granting access to your information where necessary, and using security credentials to protect stored Personally Identifiable Information (PII) so that anonymous administrators cannot access the data.

● **Use of cookies and similar technologies** : we use cookies and similar information-gathering technologies such as web beacons and Web Storage API on the websites including essential, functional, analytical and targeting cookies.

● **GDPR and Transfers of information outside the European Economic Area** : We transfer information outside of the European Economic Area including to the United States. Where we do so, we will ensure appropriate safeguards are in place.

● **Your rights in relation to your information**

o to access your information and to receive information about its use

o to have your information corrected and/or completed

o to have your information deleted

o to restrict the use of your information

o to receive your information in a portable format

o to object to the use of your information

o to withdraw your consent to the use of your information

o to complain to a supervisory authority

● **Sensitive personal information** : we do not knowingly or intentionally collect what is commonly referred to as ‘sensitive personal information’. Please do not submit sensitive personal information about you to us. For more information, please see the main section below entitled **Sensitive Personal Information**.

The data controller in respect of the websites is Maven Coalition, Inc. (a Nevada corporation) of 1500 Fourth Avenue, Suite 200, Seattle, WA 98101, along with the Channel Partner connected with each Channel. You can contact us by writing to 1500 Fourth Avenue, Suite 200, Seattle, WA 98101 or sending an email to privacy@maven.io.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us.

We collect and use information from website visitors in accordance with this section and the section entitled **Disclosure and additional uses of your information**.

 **Web service log information**

We use a third party service to host the websites called Amazon Web Services, the privacy policy of which is available here: <https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/>. The website services automatically log the IP address you use to access the websites as well as other information about your visit such as the pages accessed, information requested, the date and time of the request, the source of your access to the websites (e.g. the website or URL (link) which referred you to the websites), and your browser version and operating system and Browser User Agent string.

Our services are located in the United States. If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA) you can find further information on transfers of your information to the United States and information on the safeguards used, please see the section of this privacy policy entitled **GDPR and Transfers of information outside the European Economic Area**.

 **Cookies and similar technologies**

Cookies are data files which are sent from a website to a browser to record information about users for various purposes. We use cookies and similar technologies on the websites, including essential, functional, analytical and targeting cookies and web beacons, and our Web Storage API is used to store device ID to identify anonymous devices.

You can reject some or all of the cookies we use on or via the websites by changing your browser settings or opting out of our consent control when it is presented to the user, but doing so can impair your ability to use the websites or some or all of its features. For further information about cookies, including how to change your browser settings, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or see our cookies policy.

We collect and use information from individuals who contact us in accordance with this section and the section entitled **Disclosure and additional uses of your information**.

When you send an email to an email address displayed on the websites we collect your email address and any other information you provide in that email (such as your name, telephone number and the information contained in any signature block in your email).

 _Transfer and storage of your information_

We use a third party email provider to store emails you send us. Our third party email provider is Google G Suite. Their privacy policy is available here: <https://policies.google.com/privacy/>.

If you are located in the European Economic Area, emails you send us will be stored outside the European Economic Area on our third party email provider’s servers in the United States. For further information please see the section of this privacy policy entitled **GDPR and Transfers of information outside the European Economic Area**.

When you contact us by phone, we collect your phone number and any information provide to us during your conversation with us. We do not record phone calls, however we if you elect to leave a voicemail, that message will be recorded and stored by the applicable service provided.

 _Transfer and storage of your information_

Information about your call, such as your phone number and the date and time of your call, is processed by the applicable telephone service provider.

If you are located in the European Economic Area, information about your phone call will be stored by our third party telephone service in the United States. For further information about the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the European Economic Area, see the section of this privacy policy below entitled **GDPR and Transfers of information outside the European Economic Area**.

If you contact us by mail, we will collect any information you provide to us in any mail communications you send us.

We collect and use information from individuals who interact with particular features of the websites in accordance with this section and the section entitled **Disclosure and additional uses of your information**.

 **Registering on the websites**

When you register and create an account on the websites, we collect the following information: email address and password. You may also elect to create an account using your existing Facebook or Google profile. If you create an account using your Facebook profile we will receive your public profile your friend list and email, although Facebook will enable you to opt out of providing your friend list and email. If you create an account using your Google profile (if any) we will receive your public profile and email. 

We may provide you a way to link your account or otherwise access the services provided on the websites through the use of social media websites such as Facebook or Twitter. To the extent you elect to link your account to a social media account, you agree to accept any and all terms and conditions of use and privacy policies to such social media providers and acknowledge that the [Terms of Use](https://www.themaven.net/the-maven/pages/foGOgUjmake_KQnpC4KDVw) and this Privacy Policy may be subject to the terms of use and privacy policies of such social media providers. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of such other websites or services to understand their information practices.

If you do not provide the mandatory information required by the registration form, you will not be able to register or create an account on the websites, and will not be able to post comments or stories, access premium content or contact other users using our platform.

We also collect optional information that you submit to us, such as Username, Display Name, Biographical Information, Contact Phone and Contact Address.

 _Transfer and storage of your information_

Information you submit to us via the registration form on the websites will be stored on our third party hosting provider’s servers in the United States. Our third party hosting provider is Amazon Web Services. Their privacy policy is available here: <https://aws.amazon.com/privacy>.

If you are located in the European Economic Area, for further information about the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the European Economic Area, see the section of this privacy policy below entitled **GDPR and Transfers of information outside the European Economic Area**.

You also may provide information to be published or displayed (“posted”) on public areas of the website, or transmitted to other users of the website or third parties, which we refer to as “User Contributions”. Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to others at your own risk. Although you may set certain privacy settings for such information by logging into your account profile, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. Additionally, we cannot control the actions of other users of the website with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed by any other visitors of the website.

 **Notifications and Other Emails**

After registering on the websites, you will automatically receive email notifications if another user replies to a post or comment you make on the website. You may also receive email newsletters directly from the Channel Partner of the particular channel you registered on or any channel you choose to “Follow”. You may also choose to receive email notifications when new content is posted. 

_Transfer and storage of your information_

We use a third party service to send out our notifications and administer our mailing list, Amazon Simple Email Service (SES). Their privacy policy is available here: <https://aws.amazon.com/privacy>.

If you are located in the European Economic Area, information you submit to subscribe for our notifications will be stored on our servers in United States. For further information about the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the European Economic Area, see the section of this privacy policy below entitled **Transfers of your information outside the European Economic Area**.

Emails sent from Channel Partners may be sent with a variety of email services unconnected with the websites, and controlled by the Channel Partner. Please consult the privacy policy of the relevant email provider, which is typically disclosed in the footer of the email.

We collect and use information from individuals who place an order on the websites in accordance with this section and the section entitled **Disclosure and additional uses of your information**.

 **Information collected when you place an order**

When you place an order for a membership, subscription or premium access in connection with a Channel, you must first register as described under **Registering on the websites** above. If you do not provide the mandatory registration information, you will not be able to purchase memberships, subscriptions or premium access from our Channel Partners on the websites.

We also collect optional information from you if you choose to provide it, such as your contact phone number and mailing address.

After you place an order on the websites you will need to make payment for the goods or services you have ordered. In order to process your payment we use a third party payment processor, Stripe. Stripe collects, uses and processes your information, including payment information, in accordance with their privacy policies. Their privacy policy is available here: <https://stripe.com/us/privacy>.

 _Transfer and storage of your information_

Stripe is located in the United States and information relating to the processing of your payment is stored on its servers in the United States.

If you are located in the European Economic Area, for further information about the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the European Economic Area, see the section of this privacy policy below entitled **GDPR and Transfers of information outside the European Economic Area**.

This section sets out how we obtain or collect information about you from third parties. Channel Partners may provide us with your email address if you have previously provided it to them.

Generally, we do not receive information about you from third parties. Should you elect to create an account using your existing Facebook or Google profile, you will authorize us to receive certain information from Facebook or Google, as the case may be.

It is also possible that third parties with whom we have had no prior contact may provide us with information about you.

Information we obtain from third parties will generally be your name and contact details, but will include any additional information about you which they provide to us.

This section sets out the circumstances in which will disclose information about you to third parties and any additional purposes for which we use your information.

 **Disclosure of your information to service providers**

We use a number of third parties to provide us with services which are necessary to run our business or to assist us with running our business and who process your information for us on our behalf. These include the following:

Our third party service providers are located in the United States.

Your information will be shared with these service providers where necessary to provide you with the service you have requested, whether that is accessing websites or ordering goods and services from us.

 **Disclosure of your information to other third parties**

We disclose your information to other third parties in specific circumstances, as set out below.

 _Providing information to third parties such as Google._

Google collects information through our use of Google Analytics on the websites. Google uses this information, including IP addresses and information from cookies, for a number of purposes, such as improving its Google Analytics service. Information is shared with Google on an aggregated and anonymized basis. To find out more about what information Google collects, how it uses this information and how to control the information sent to Google, please see the following page: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.

 _Transfer and storage of your information_

Information collected by Google Analytics is stored on Google’s servers in the United States of America.

If you are located in the European Economic Area, for further information about the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the European Economic Area, see the section of this privacy policy below entitled **GDPR and Transfers of information outside the European Economic Area**.

 **Where necessary, further information on each of these third parties, which are related to the running of our business, is set out below.**

We share information with our auditors. For example, we share invoices we issue and receive with our auditors for the purpose of completing periodic reports. Our auditors are BDO USA, LLP and are located in the United States.

Occasionally, we obtain advice from advisors, such as financial advisors, lawyers and public relations professionals. We will share your information with these third parties only where it is necessary to enable these third parties to be able to provide us with the relevant advice.

Our advisors include Golenbock Eiseman, Assor, Bell & Peskoe, LLP, DWC Law Firm, Peterson Russell Kelley and B. Riley FBR, Inc. Our advisors are located in the United States.

Occasionally, we use independent contractors in our business. Your information will be shared with independent contractors only where it is necessary for them to perform the function we have hired them perform in relation to our business.

Our independent contractors are generally computer engineers located in the United States.

We may share your information with a prospective or actual purchaser or seller in the context of a business or asset sale or acquisition by us, a merger or similar business combination event, whether actual or potential.

 _Disclosure and use of your information for legal reasons_

 _Indicating possible criminal acts or threats to public security to a competent authority_

If we suspect that criminal or potential criminal conduct has been occurred, we will in certain circumstances need to contact an appropriate authority, such as the police. This could be the case, for instance, if we suspect that we fraud or a cybercrime has been committed or if we receive threats or malicious communications towards us or third parties.

We will generally only need to process your information for this purpose if you were involved or affected by such an incident in some way.

 _In connection with the enforcement or potential enforcement our legal rights_

We will use your information in connection with the enforcement or potential enforcement of our legal rights, including, for example, sharing information with debt collection agencies if you do not pay amounts owed to us when you are contractually obliged to do so. Our legal rights may be contractual (where we have entered into a contract with you) or non-contractual (such as legal rights that we have under copyright law or tort law).

 _In connection with a legal or potential legal dispute or proceedings_

We may need to use your information if we are involved in a dispute with you or a third party for example, either to resolve the dispute or as part of any mediation, arbitration or court resolution or similar process.

 _For ongoing compliance with laws, regulations and other legal requirements_

We will use and process your information in order to comply with legal obligations to which we are subject. For example, we may need to disclose your information pursuant to a court order or subpoena if we receive one.

This section sets out how long we retain your information. We have set out specific retention periods where possible. Where that has not been possible, we have set out the criteria we use to determine the retention period.

 _Server log information_ : we retain information on our server logs indefinitely or until you request that it be deleted.

 _Order information_ : when you place an order for goods and services, we retain that information for six years following the end of the financial year in which you placed your order, in accordance with our legal obligation to keep records for tax purposes.

 _Correspondence and inquiries_ : when you make an inquiry or correspond with us for any reason, whether by email or by phone, we will retain your information for at least as long as it takes to respond to and resolve your inquiry.

We store other user data until will be deleted on user request.

 **Criteria for determining retention periods**

In any other circumstances, we will retain your information for no longer than necessary, taking into account the following:

● the purpose(s) and use of your information both now and in the future (such as whether it is necessary to continue to store that information in order to continue to perform our obligations under a contract with you or to contact you in the future);

● whether we have any legal obligation to continue to process your information (such as any record-keeping obligations imposed by relevant law or regulation);

● whether we have any legal basis to continue to process your information (such as your consent);

● how valuable your information is (both now and in the future);

● any relevant agreed industry practices on how long information should be retained;

● the levels of risk, cost and liability involved with us continuing to hold the information;

● how hard it is to ensure that the information can be kept up to date and accurate; and

● any relevant surrounding circumstances (such as the nature and status of our relationship with you).

We take appropriate technical and organizational measures to secure your information and to protect it against unauthorised or unlawful use and accidental loss or destruction, including:

● only sharing and providing access to your information to the minimum extent necessary, subject to confidentiality restrictions where appropriate, and on an anonymised basis wherever possible;

● using secure servers to store your information, using authentication that only our operations team can access;

● verifying the identity of any individual who requests access to information prior to granting them access to information;

● using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software to encrypt and any payment transactions you make on or via the websites; and

● only transferring your information via closed system or encrypted data transfers.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of the websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the websites. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the websites.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to the websites. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the websites.

 **Transmission of information to us by email**

Transmission of information over the internet is not entirely secure, and if you submit any information to us over the internet (whether by email, via the websites or any other means), you do so entirely at your own risk.

We cannot be responsible for any costs, expenses, loss of profits, harm to reputation, damages, liabilities or any other form of loss or damage suffered by you as a result of your decision to transmit information to us by such means.

If you are located in the European Economic Area, your information will be transferred and stored in the United States Area (EEA) in the circumstances set out below. We will also transfer your information outside the EEA or to an international organization in order to comply with legal obligations to which we are subject (compliance with a court order, for example). Where we are required to do so, we will ensure appropriate safeguards and protections are in place.

Information collected when you visit the websites is stored on the servers of our third party hosting provider, Amazon Web Services, in the United States, the privacy policy of which is available here: <https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/>.

Information you submit to us by email is stored on our third party email provider’s servers in the United States. Our third party email provider is Google G Suite. Their privacy policy is available here: <https://policies.google.com/privacy/>.

Information you submit to us when you sign up for our notifications is stored on our third party mailing list provider’s servers in the United States. Our third party mailing list provider is: _Amazon Simple Email Service_. You can access their privacy policy here: [_https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/_](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/).

Information collected by Google Analytics (your IP address and actions you take in relation to the websites) is transferred outside the EEA and stored on Google’s servers in the United States. You can access Google’s privacy policy here: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

Our legal basis for collection and processing of personal data is as follows:

● consent explicitly given by you for the purpose requested;

● legal compliance and/or vital interest, as mandated by a valid and binding request from an applicable government entity with proper jurisdiction;

● contractual performance, for example with respect to activities initiated by you on the website;

● legitimate interests pursued by us (or third parties we use) include specific activities initiated by you on the service and/or fraud/anti-spam protection, security, authentication, load-balancing, and other fundamental provisioning and protections for both registered and unregistered users of the website.

Subject to certain limitations on certain rights, you have the following rights in relation to your information, which you can exercise by writing to 1500 Fourth Avenue, Suite 200, Seattle, WA 98101 or sending an email to [privacy@maven.io](mailto:privacy@maven.io).

● **to request access to your information** and information related to our use and processing of your information;

● **to request the correction or deletion** of your information;

● **to request that we restrict our use** of your information;

● **to receive information which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format** (e.g. a CSV file) and the right to have that information transferred to another data controller (including a third party data controller);

● **to object to the processing of your information for certain purposes** (for further information, see the section below entitled **Your right to object to the processing of your information for certain purposes** ); and

● **to withdraw your consent to our use of your information** at any time where we rely on your consent to use or process that information. Please note that if you withdraw your consent, this will not affect the lawfulness of our use and processing of your information on the basis of your consent before the point in time when you withdraw your consent. To withdraw your consent, click here: <http://themaven.net/the-maven/_privacypreferences>

If you are located in the European Economic Area, in accordance with Article 77 of the General Data Protection Regulation, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or of an alleged infringement of the General Data Protection Regulation. You can also find out further information about your rights, as well as information on any limitations which apply to those rights, by reading the underlying legislation contained in Articles 12 to 22 and 34 of the General Data Protection Regulation, which is available here: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/reform/files/regulation_oj_en.pdf>**.**

 **Verifying your identity where you request access to your information**

Where you request access to your information, we are required by law to use all reasonable measures to verify your identity before doing so.

These measures are designed to protect your information and to reduce the risk of identity fraud, identity theft or general unauthorised access to your information.

 _How we verify your identity_

Where we possess appropriate information about you on file, we will attempt to verify your identity using that information.

If it is not possible to identity you from such information, or if we have insufficient information about you, we may require original or certified copies of certain documentation in order to be able to verify your identity before we are able to provide you with access to your information.

We will be able to confirm the precise information we require to verify your identity in your specific circumstances if and when you make such a request.

You have the following rights in relation to your information, which you may exercise in the same way as you may exercise by writing to 1500 Fourth Avenue, Suite 200, Seattle, WA 98101 or sending an email to [_privacy@maven.io_](mailto:privacy@maven.io):

● to object to us using or processing your information where we use or process it in order to **carry out a task in the public interest** **or for our legitimate interests** , including ‘profiling’ (i.e. analyzing or predicting your behaviour based on your information) based on any of these purposes; and

● to object to us using or processing your information for **direct marketing purposes** (including any profiling we engage in that is related to such direct marketing).

You may also exercise your right to object to us using or processing your information for direct marketing purposes by:

● **clicking the unsubscribe link** contained at the bottom of any marketing email we send to you and following the instructions which appear in your browser following your clicking on that link;

● **sending an email** to privacy@maven.io, asking that we stop sending you marketing communications or by including the words “OPT OUT”.

‘Sensitive personal information’ is information about an individual that reveals their racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, genetic information, biometric information for the purpose of uniquely identifying an individual, information concerning health or information concerning a natural person’s sex life or sexual orientation.

We do not knowingly or intentionally collect sensitive personal information from individuals, and you must not submit sensitive personal information to us.

If, however, you inadvertently or intentionally transmit sensitive personal information to us, you will be considered to have explicitly consented to us processing that sensitive personal information. We will use and process your sensitive personal information for the purposes of deleting it.

We update and amend our Privacy Policy from time to time.

 _Minor changes to our Privacy Policy_

Where we make minor changes to our Privacy Policy, we will update our Privacy Policy with a new effective date stated at the beginning of it. Our processing of your information will be governed by the practices set out in that new version of the Privacy Policy from its effective date onwards.

 _Major changes to our Privacy Policy or the purposes for which we process your information_

Where we make major changes to our Privacy Policy or intend to use your information for a new purpose or a different purpose than the purposes for which we originally collected it, we will notify you by email (where possible) or by posting a notice on the websites.

We will provide you with the information about the change in question and the purpose and any other relevant information before we use your information for that new purpose.

Wherever required, we will obtain your prior consent before using your information for a purpose that is different from the purposes for which we originally collected it.

The websites is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any information to or on the Website. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 years old. If you are under 13 years old, do not use or provide any information on the Website or on or through any of its features/register on the Website, make any purchases through the Website, use any of the interactive or public comment features of the Website or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child younger than 13 years of age, please contact us at notifications@maven.io.

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of the Website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to service@maven.io.
